saurabh bansal

Technical Team Lead at Marin Software

sauraviit@gmail.com

Summary

Database developer with more than eight years of experience in designing, developing and supporting enterprise software applications and tools.

Skills:- Data warehousing, ETL, SSIS, RedShift, Sql Server, MongoDB, Node.js

Certifications

Cloudera Developer Training for Apache Hadoop

Cloudera December 2012 to December 2012

edX Verified Certificate for Introduction to Big Data with Apache Spark

edX

Experience

Technical Team Lead at Marin Software

January 2014 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Technical team lead for Marin Labs. Marin Labs offers customers access to leading edge research and development, advanced partner integrations, and more.

Architected and developed a platform that is very scalable, has short release cycles and very easy to deploy. This platform works in parallel with the legacy system which provides marin an edge over other competitors when it comes to new advance features.

Technology used:- NodeJs, MongoDB, RedShift, ActiveMQ, SSIS, Sql Server

Senior Integration Specialist at Marin Software

October 2010 - January 2014 (3 years 4 months)

I engineered an ETL framework for large-scale job processing and auditing, which automates campaign management in order to ensure that online advertisements always accurately represent product inventory.

Designed and coded a web interface to this ETL framework for supporting new implementations, reducing the implementation time from days to hours.

Tools and Framework:- Hadoop, Hive Pig, SSIS, SqlServer, C#, Asp.net

ETL/ Data warehouse developer at Nevada Department of Education

January 2008 - October 2010 (2 years 10 months)

SQLServer 2005/2008, SSIS ,SSRS, Powershell, VB.NET, C#, XML, XSLT, Java, Web Services , API

Graduate Engineer Trainee at Otis Elevator Company

2004 - 2006 (2 years)

Sqlserver Database Development. Vb Scripting. c#

Projects

SharpHadoop

October 2013 to Present

Members:saurabh bansal

SharpHadoop facilitates access to WebHDFS from .Net.

The library can easily be dependencies and solely relies on the .net standard library

https://sharphadoop.codeplex.com/

Education

Illinois Institute of Technology

Masters of Science, Information Technology, 2007 - 2009

Punjab Technical University

Bachelors of Technology, Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering, 2001 - 2005

Skills & Expertise

Microsoft SQL Server

SSIS

SSRS

C#

Hive

Java

ASP.NET

VB.NET

Powershell

ETL Tools

Business Intelligence

Business Analysis

XML

MySQL

Requirements Analysis

Hadoop

Talend Open Studio

Subversion

Data Analysis

Databases
Software Project Management
Data Warehousing
REST
JavaScript
Software Development
Integration
SQL

saurabh bansal

Technical Team Lead at Marin Software

sauraviit@gmail.com



2 person has recommended saurabh

"We assigned Saurabh our most complex database tasks. He analyzed the data warehouse's data structures and processing requirements, determined the best solution, and developed the Extraction, Transformation, and Loading (ETL) packages for implementation via SQL Server Integration Services. He reduced the daily data loading times, that previously took hours, tenfold. He was also our lead on the design of Analysis Cubes for Business Intelligence and data analysis. He was always forthright about issues with the data and provided solid assessments of the corrective actions needed to achieve his objectives. On a personal level, he was always considerate of others and always collaborated to ensure his work integrated accurately with the rest of the team."

- Kenneth Nelmes, was saurabh's client

"Saurabh was a detail oriented employee that always found a way to get the job done no matter what the obstacles were. He was very eager and a joy to work with. His peer's worked very well with him and could always count on him and his work. I would recommend Saurabh with no reservations and wish him the very best in his future endeavors."

— Shawn Franklin, managed saurabh at Nevada Department of Education

Contact saurabh on LinkedIn